Guide to the American Association of University Professors, University of Houston Chapter Records
University of Houston Libraries
American Association of University Professors, University of Houston Chapter Records
1958-1968
1969-071
American Association of University Professors. University of Houston Chapter
1.00 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
The American Association of University Professors, University of Houston Chapter Records consists mainly of documents directly related to the organization including the Constitution, minutes, bank statements, letters, correspondence, membership lists, and newsletters.
Historical Note:
The purpose of the University of Houston Chapter of the American Association of University Professors (AAUP) was to "facilitate a more effective cooperation among teachers and research scholars in the university community for the promotion of the interests of higher education and research and in general to increase the usefulness and advance the standards, ideals, and welfare of the profession."
As cited in the organization's Constitution, membership and voting was limited to members of the faculty of the University of Houston who were Active or Emeritus Members and Junior Members of the American Association of University Professors. Associate Members of the American Association of University Professors could be invited to meetings as the Executive Council deemed necessary.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
American Association of University Professors. University of Houston Chapter; University of Houston; University of Houston -- Faculty
Genre/Form of Material:
Bank statements; Correspondence; Minutes; Newsletters; Records (documents)
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Arrangement of Materials:
The collection arrived at the archives in relatively good order, which has been maintained where possible. For preservation and access reasons the collection has been re-boxed and re-foldered. New folder titles conform, as closely as possible, to original folder titles, except when the original was obviously incomplete, incorrect, or confusing. Original folder and item order has been maintained whenever possible. Exceptions were made when folders were obviously misfiled or when no order was apparent.
Scope and Contents
The American Association of University Professors, University of Houston Chapter Records consists mainly of documents directly related to the organization including the Constitution, minutes, bank statements, letters, correspondence, membership lists, and newsletters.
Detailed List of Contents
- Constitution (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Minutes, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Minutes, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Minutes, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Minutes, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Minutes, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Minutes, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Account Authorization & I.D. Card (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bank Statements, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bank Statements, 1964/1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bank Statements, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Chapter Letters, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Chapter Letters, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Chapter Letters, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Chapter Letters, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Chapter Letters, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Executive Council Minutes, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Executive Council Minutes, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Finances & Bills Paid, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Finances & Bills Paid, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Information for Chapter Officers (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Mailing Addresses (Members) (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Membership Applications & Reply Forms (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Membership, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Membership, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Membership, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Membership, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Membership, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Membership, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Membership, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Membership, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Memo/Notices, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Memos/Newsletters, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Memos/Newsletters/Notices, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 41)
- National Membership Brochures (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Notes, Directions & Procedures (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Planning Committee (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Salary Charts & Information on Academic Salaries, 1960/1961-1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Statements of Council Nominees (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Statements on Government and College Universities (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Texas Conference, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Treasurer's Report, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- UH Campus Maps (Box 1, Folder 50)
- West Texas State University - 1967 Study of Texas College Libraries (Box 1, Folder 51)